(soft piano music)
In this video, we're going to actually download
and install Python 3 from python.org on a Macintosh.
If your Macintosh for years has wonderfully come
with Python 2, so if I type Python minus minus version,
then if I type that, I see that I've got Python 2.0.
What we want to do is, in addition, install Python 3.
One of these days, Macintosh might upgrade
their distributed version of Python 3,
but there's so many things inside Mac
that depend on Python 2, I'm going to expect
that it will always be named Python 3,
which is what we're going to call it in a second.
So, here I am at the python.org downloads,
and I'm going to download Python 3.
You click here, and I've actually got it sitting here
in downloads already, because I always do that.
And so, I'm going to install this.
There is the installer.
I'm going to say continue, continue, continue.
Of course I agree, I read all that really fast,
and now I'm going to install it.
(soft piano music)
Okay, so now, that means if I run a terminal,
so this, of course, is start run terminal.
So, Python 2 is still there,
but Python 3 is also now involved there,
so we should have Python 3 installed.
So, we installed Python 3.6, and so there we go,
and that's all it takes to install Python 3
on the Macintosh.
So, let's write our first little Python program.
I'm going to, I like Adam,
and so I've got this Adam editor, it's adam.io.
Right here, adam.io, download and install the Adam editor.
I like it because Adam works the same
on both Windows, Mac, and Linux,
and it has syntax highlighting,
and so I really like things like that.
So, I'm going to make myself a simple Python program.
Hello, world, like we always do.
Now, you'll notice that it's not syntax highlighting yet,
but I'm going to do a file, save, oopsie daisy.
File, save as, and I'm going to go into my desktop,
and I'm going to make a folder called py4e.
I'm just going to, let's call this hello.py.
Oh, crud.
Gotta rename it, rename it.
I ended up with two dots.
Hello.py, there we are.
And so now I'm here, and I'm in my home folder.
I can go in my desktop, and I can go into that new folder
I made, Python for Everybody, and I can see the files.
Now, there are ways to run this,
and I really want you to learn the terminal
so that you really know what you're doing.
And so here we are, we are in the folder that has the Python,
and then all we do to run it is we say python3 hello.py,
and there we go, and of course, this is python3,
because I'm using parentheses there.
So, instead of double quotes, but python2 is still there,
and of course, if you just run python hello.py,
it'll be a syntax error, or not.
Must be they added something.
(laughs)
Yeah, because Python is still version,
still version two, but apparently they allowed print
in the latest version of python2, so away we go.
Okay, so again, thanks for watching.
I hope this was helpful to you to get python3 installed
on your Macintosh.
(jazz music)